<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<ESRI_ItemInformation Culture='en-US'>
<name>f88b2b0d922642e689864cbd3409c177</name>
<guid>F74A962D-4FC3-418C-A989-548E96913A4A</guid>
<catalogpath></catalogpath>
<snippet></snippet>
<description>Magnitude of habitat fragmentation indicated by largest patch size, by terrestrial ecoregion. 







We considered agriculture, urban infrastructure, roads, and railroads as &amp;ldquo;fragmenting&amp;rdquo; features to the landscape and areas not converted to agriculture, urban infrastructure, roads, or railroads as &amp;ldquo;nonfragmented&amp;rdquo; terrestrial landscape patches. We used input spatial data from JRC&amp;rsquo;s GLC 2000 (2003), CIESIN et al. (2004), Defense Mapping Agency (1992), and South American Conservation Region (2005). To produce the data, we constructed a global map grid of fragmenting features (Mollweide projection, based on the WGS 1984 datum; 1 km2 resolution); this grid was then combined with the GLC 2000, adding a new &amp;ldquo;fragmenting features&amp;rdquo; class to the GLC 2000 map. We then extracted a window around the area of each ecoregion in a way that avoided truncating landscape patches with the ecoregion boundary, and measured landscape fragmentation characteristics using Fragstats (McGarigal et al. 2002). The map shows one of these characteristics: the largest patch size by ecoregion. 







These data were derived by The Nature Conservancy, and were displayed in a map published in The Atlas of Global Conservation (Hoekstra et al., University of California Press, 2010).  More information at http://nature.org/atlas.







The primary resources we used to develop this map were the following:



CIESIN (Center for International Earth Science Information Network), IFPRI (International Food Policy Research Institute), the World Bank, and CIAT (Centro Internacional de Agricultura Tropical). 2004. Global Rural-Urban Mapping Project (GRUMP): Urban Extents, Columbia University Palisades, New York, USA. Available at http://sedac.ciesin.columbia.edu/gpw/. Digital media.







Defense Mapping Agency. 1992. Digital Chart of the World [4 CDs]. Updated 1996. Fairfax, VA: Author.







Joint Research Centre of the European Commission (JRC). 2003. GLC 2000: Global Land Cover Mapping for the Year 2000. Ispra, Italy: European Commission Joint Research Centre, Institute for Environment and Sustainability. Available at www-tem.jrc.it/glc2000. Digital media.







McGarigal, K., S. A. Cushman, M. C. Neel, and E. Ene. 2002. FRAGSTATS: Spatial Pattern Analysis Program for Categorical Maps. Amherst: University of Massachusetts. Available at www.umass.edu/landeco/research/fragstats/fragstats.html.







South American Conservation Region. 2005. V&amp;iacute;as de Sur America. Geographic Information System data set. The Nature Conservancy, Arlington, Virginia, USA.

This dataset was uploaded to Data Basin and is available with additional information at: http://app.databasin.org/app/pages/datasetPage.jsp?id=f88b2b0d922642e689864cbd3409c177</description>
<summary></summary>
<title>Magnitude of Habitat Fragmentation by Terrestrial Ecoregion</title>
<tags></tags>
<type>Layer Package</type>
<typekeywords>
<typekeyword>Shapefile Feature Class</typekeyword>
<typekeyword>Layer Package</typekeyword>
<typekeyword>Data</typekeyword>
<typekeyword>ArcMap</typekeyword>
<typekeyword>.lpk</typekeyword>
</typekeywords>
<thumbnail>thumbnail/thumbnail.png</thumbnail>
<documentation></documentation>
<url></url>
<datalastmodifiedtime></datalastmodifiedtime>
<extent>
<xmin>-179.999988600612</xmin>
<ymin>-89.8919732774029</ymin>
<xmax>179.999988600612</xmax>
<ymax>83.6231251716938</ymax>
</extent>
<spatialreference>GCS_WGS_1984</spatialreference>
<accessinformation></accessinformation>
</ESRI_ItemInformation>
